>> Hey, welcome back, everyone.
>> 嘿，欢迎大家回来。
Our next session has a set of
我们接下来的环节有一组
seven short presentations and
我们接下来的环节有一组七个简短的报告，
will be chaired by Jay Misra.
将由Jay Misra主持。
Jay is a computer science professor
Jay是一位计算机科学教授。
at New Mexico State University.
在新墨西哥州立大学。
His research interests
他的研究兴趣包括算法和协议
include algorithm and protocol
包括算法和协议
design and development for
设计和开发用于
anonymity and security,
匿名性和安全性，
as well as network survivability.
以及网络生存能力。
Jay, go ahead, please.
Jay，请继续。
>> Thanks, Lotfi. Welcome everyone
>> 谢谢，洛特菲。欢迎大家
to this short presentation session.
参加这个简短的介绍会。
Like Lotfi mentioned, we'll
像洛特菲提到的，我们将会
have several of our panellists,
我们将会有好几位小组成员，
almost seven attendees making presentations.
我们将有将近七位与会者进行演讲。
Without spending much time, let
我们将不会花费太多时间，请允许我介绍我们的第一位演讲者。
me introduce our first presenter.
让我来介绍我们的第一位演讲者。
Our first presenter is Dr Xtian,
让我来介绍我们的第一位演讲者，Xtian 博士，
who received his PhD from
获得他的博士学位来自
the Department of
电子与计算机工程系
Electrical and Computer Engineering
电子与计算机工程
from the University of Connecticut in 2010.
他于2010年从康涅狄格大学毕业。
He joined Intelligent Fusion Technologies
他加入了智能融合技术公司。
in Germantown,
在Germantown，
Maryland in 2010 and has done
2010年在马里兰州，并且已经完成了
much research in satellite communications,
卫星通信领域的大量研究，
cognitive radio systems,
认知无线电系统，
and communication networks.
和通信网络。
He's now the Network and
他现在是网络和通信研究主任，在
Communication Research Director at
Intelligent Fusion Technology.
Intelligent Fusion Technology.
智能融合技术。
Go ahead Dr Xtian.
请继续，Xtian博士。
>> [NOISE] Thank you.
>> [噪音] 谢谢。
>> We can't see you clear.
>> 我们看不清楚你。
>> Off the screen. Good afternoon.
>> 屏幕外。下午好。
We're happy to attend this workshop.
我们很高兴参加这个研讨会。
We'll start work on NDN.
我们将开始进行NDN的工作。
This is work from
这是工作来自
Intelligent Fusion Technology
智能融合技术
with Air Force Research Lab.
与美国空军研究实验室合作。
This top we'll talk about the method
这次我们将讨论的方法
for NDN based data transfer
在基于NDN的数据传输中
in multi-path networking environments.
在多路径网络环境中。
Here's the problem description.
Here's the problem description.
In this part, I will try to apply NDN
在这部分，我将尝试应用NDN。
to satellites SATCOM networks
到卫星SATCOM网络
and applications.
和应用场景。
There are many scenarios,
有很多场景，
that's network environments,
网络环境下，
smart multi-path.
智能多路径。
For example, the satellite constellation has
例如，卫星星座具有
LEO satellite constellation station or
LEO卫星星座站或
has multiple paths like oscillation coverage.
具有类似振荡覆盖的多条路径。
It appears in the multi-path.
它出现在多路径中。
Another case is when you have
另一个情况是当你有
multiple networks from
多个网络来自~!@#$%^&*()
different providers like Darla Nicolson,
不同的供应商，例如Darla Nicolson，
Aldi networks, all personal networks.
奥乐齐网络，所有个人网络。
We're looking into the application of
我们正在研究应用
NDN as an OLA network
NDN作为一个OLA网络
to be able to utilize
能够利用
the multi-path communication network.
多路径通信网络。
Specifically, we want to
具体来说，我们想要
get that improvement for multi-path like
获得类似多路径的那种改进
a network throughput and as a first goal
网络吞吐量作为首要目标
and maybe also an improvement
可能还有所改进
in robustness for certain applications.
在某些应用程序中的鲁棒性上。
There are a few challenges with multi-path.
多路径存在一些挑战。
First is the multi-path,
多路径是首要的，
especially if you have
尤其是如果你有
a satellite network that
一颗卫星网络，如果你有，是一种不同的性质，比如
is a different nature like
是一种不同的性质，比如
a LEO network and lowers
一个低地球轨道(LEO)网络并降低了~!@#$%^&*()
orbit or GEO is a high orbit.
轨道或GEO是一个高轨道。
The delay difference can be very large,
时延差异可能非常大，
and so that's the first challenge.
因此，这是第一个挑战。
So consider this specific scenario,
因此，请考虑这个特定的场景，
you have one consumer and one data producer.
你有一个消费者和一个数据生产者。
You want to communicate,
你想要沟通，
so these multi-path network environments.
所以这些多路径网络环境。
The other one is the end-to-end circle levels
另一个是端到端的圆形层级。
available from different paths is unknown,
可从不同路径获得的是未知的，
so you need to learn them.
所以你需要学习它们。
The third one is
第三个是
the potential coupling of the multi-paths,
多路径之间可能的耦合，
between a consumer and a data producer.
在消费者和数据生产者之间。
That is some challenges
这是一些挑战。
in this environment for achieving high.
在这种环境下实现高成就。
Though we talk about solutions because we
虽然我们讨论解决方案是因为我们
also have Professor Misra from UCLA.
我们也有来自加州大学洛杉矶分校的米斯拉教授。
He'll help you answer this.
他会帮你回答这个问题。
The first solution is just,
第一个解决方案是公正的，
I think such emphysema UCLA,
我认为这种肺气肿是加州大学洛杉矶分校的，
he talked about earlier, it's
他之前谈到的，就是
dynamic and multi-path forwarding.
他之前谈到的，就是动态的和多路径转发。
They tried to develop
他们试图开发
unjust control rate
不公正的控制速率
based on congestion control.
基于拥塞控制。
Basically you match the sending rate and
基本上你匹配发送速率和
the interest package sending rate under
基本上你匹配发送速率和利息包发送率下的
the data package coming back.
数据包的回传。
I tried to deal with
我尝试处理
the delay difference in
延迟差在于~!@#$%^&*()
different assets are a unique case.
不同资产是一个独特的案例。
You have ash in the middle network.
你的中间网络有灰尘。
But it's so
但它是如此
the consumer side is pretty simple.
消费者端相当简单。
In that case, it's
在那种情况下，它是
not easier but just
不是更容易，而只是
control the sending rate,
控制发送速率，
but our forwarders need to try
但是我们的转发器需要尝试
to match the incoming interest rate
以匹配进入的利率
and the package return rate also,
以及包裹回报率也是如此，
it has more complex
它更为复杂
decision-making with
决策与
the forwarding decisions,
转发决策，
like which one to use a how much report to
喜欢哪一个，以及报告使用了多少
apply on it's your face available.
将其涂抹在你的脸上。
The data consumer side just uses
数据消费方仅仅使用
single congestion to control.
单一拥堵控制。
For other site has
对于其他站点有
more compact forwarding decision-making.
更紧凑的转发决策制定。
There are a lot of challenges,
有很多挑战，
I think in this case
我认为在这种情况下
is so the effective throughput
的有效吞吐量是如此
through the multi-path network would
通过多路径网络可以
be achieved between the consumer and
可以在消费者和
the data producer actually depends
数据生产者实际上依赖于
on the decision-makers, that are forwarders.
在决策者身上，他们是货运代理。
When you have many forwarders
当你有许多货运代理时
across a network,
跨越一个网络，
so it's a dynamic of
跨越一个网络，所以它是一个动态的
the decision-making
决策制定
and the circle levels make this,
和圆形层次使得这个，
could be challenging to handle,
可能难以处理，
especially if you have a longer delay.
尤其是如果你遇到了较长时间的延迟。
The dynamics, it's hard to predict.
这种动态，很难预测。
I think there are certain challenges
我认为存在一些挑战。
in this approach,
在这种方法中，
but it also has many benefits. Of course.
但它也有很多好处。当然。
Next is,
下一个是，
another solution we think can be applied is,
我们认为可以应用的另一个解决方案是，
we add a flow ID
我们添加了一个流ID
into the NDN interest packages.
添加到NDN兴趣包中。
It's not a part
这不是一部分
of the name of the user's name of
用户名称的名称的
the data but it's
但它是数据
just a flow ID towards the interests package.
只是一个指向利益包的流ID。
It's added by either the consumer side.
它是由消费者端添加的。
With a flow ID, basically,
有了一个流ID，基本上，
we can create water flow through the network.
我们可以通过网络创建水流。
In this example, you have a spray flows.
在这个例子中，你有一个喷雾流动。
We'll put a forwarder flighty.
我们将安排一个空运班机。
The decision-making becomes simple.
决策变得简单。
Though for a Package with
尽管对于一个包裹来说
a similar file name and different
一个相似的文件名和不同的
flow ID you may
流ID，你可能会
use different forwarding decisions.
使用不同的转发决策。
Forward interests package with
使用兴趣包进行转发
the same filename and similar filename.
相同的文件名和类似的文件名。
Of course, different segments
当然，不同的部分
and the simpler you use
和你使用的越简单
the same base before as those packages.
这些包裹之前使用的是同样的基底。
Basically, it's come words that I have
基本上，这些是我有的一些词汇。
some multi-path network [OVERLAPPING]
一些多路径网络[重叠]
environment into an environmentalist
将环境转变为环保主义者
multiple, single path.
单路径和多路径。
Use single path and
使用单一路径和
[OVERLAPPING] the consumer side.
消费者端。
Yeah, you're used to
是的，你已经习惯了
its own congest control.
它自己的拥塞控制。
Basically, in this case,
基本上，在这种情况下，
you will handle the delay variation
你将处理延迟变化。
problem with the flow ID.
流程ID存在问题。
Also forwarding decisions
还有转发决策。
either forwarders are simple.
转发器都很简单。
Though the so-called from each of
尽管所谓的“各取所需”
the passages can be effectively utilized.
这些通道可以被有效利用。
Though I think that's a few advantages
尽管我认为那有一些优势
of a bush and also
的一个灌木丛，还有
for the creation of the attacker flows,
为了创建攻击者流量，
we suggest to build
我们建议建立
the flows sequentially like,
像这样依次建立流程，
you establish the first flow.
你建立了第一个流程。
When the so-called reaches a stable level,
当所谓的达到一个稳定的水平时，
you start the next line.
你开始下一行。
Helps forwarders to identify
帮助货运代理识别
independent paths for the data transfer.
独立的数据传输路径。
That helps reduce the coupling
这有助于减少耦合。
of different paths so
不同路径因此
you get better performance.
你会获得更好的性能。
That's basically, yeah, we're
那基本上是的，我们正在
still trying to implement
我们仍在努力实施这些解决方案并观察它的工作情况。
these solutions and see how it works,
我们仍在努力实施这些解决方案并观察它的工作情况，
and maybe compare it to
和也许比较一下它与
the dynamic multi-path forwarding strategy.
动态多路径转发策略。
>> Thank you very much Dr. Xtian.
>> 非常感谢Xtian博士。
For any questions or follow up,
如有任何问题或后续事宜，
you could probably use
您可能可以使用
the Slack channel for discussion.
您可能可以使用Slack频道进行讨论。
Since we have seven
既然我们有七个
presentations and 70 minutes,
演讲和70分钟，
we basically have
我们基本上有
10 minutes per presentation.
演讲每次10分钟。
This is really interesting.
这真的很有趣。
Thank you for your presentation.
感谢您的演讲。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> The next presentation is
>> 下一个报告是
by Dr. Charif Mahmoudi,
由Charif Mahmoudi博士，
who's going to talk about
谁将要讲述
NDN for next-generation
NDN代表下一代
of factory automation.
的工厂自动化硕士学位。
Dr. Mahmoudi received the Masters
Dr. Mahmoudi received the Master's degree in Factory Automation and PhD in Computer Engineering from
and PhD in Computer Engineering from
和计算机工程博士学位来自
University of Paris EST
巴黎东方大学
in 2009 and 2014 respectively.
分别在2009年和2014年。
After that, he was a PostDoc at NIST.
在那之后，他在美国国家标准与技术研究院担任博士后。
Then he subsequently joined
然后他随后加入了
Siemens Corporate Technology as
西门子企业技术部门担任
a software architect for intelligent systems.
担任智能系统的软件架构师。
Participated as a consultant,
参与担任顾问，
then software architect for
参与担任软件架构师，
several successful telecommunication projects
参与了几个成功的电信项目
with France Telecom and Bouygues Telecom,
与法国电信和布依格电信合作，
and contributed to several research projects.
并为多个研究项目做出了贡献。
His area of interests
他的兴趣领域
are in distributed systems,
分布式系统中,
cloud computing, mobile computing,
云计算、移动计算、
and Internet of things.
和物联网。
Thank you. Please go ahead.
谢谢，请继续。
>> Yeah. I hope that you can hear me.
>> 是的。我希望你能听到我。
>> Yes, we can.
>> 是的，我们能做到。
>> Excellent. Thanks for
>> 很好。谢谢你为
the nice introduction.
很好。谢谢你为漂亮的介绍。接下来，我将分享我的屏幕和幻灯片。
I will share my screen with my slides.
我将分享我的屏幕和幻灯片。
I swear it will not be
我发誓不会是
more than 10 minutes presentation.
超过10分钟的演讲。
>> I wish we could have
>> 我希望我们能够
everybody speak for 20-25 minutes.
每个人发言20-25分钟。
It's interesting.
这很有趣。
[NOISE] [LAUGHTER] Let's bet on time.
我们来赌时间吧。
Sorry, please go ahead.
对不起，请继续。
>> Excellent. Indeed. Charif Mahmoudi
>> 极好的。确实。Charif Mahmoudi
currently working at Siemens on
目前在西门子工作，在
topics related to intelligence systems.
涉及智能系统的话题。
I do have reasonable NDN activity
我确实有合理的NDN活动。
that I would like,
我想要，
at least, to share some thoughts about.
至少，分享一些关于的想法。
Mainly, my rationale and how
至少，我的理念以及如何~!@#$%^&*()
those concepts behind NDN has been remapped,
这些NDN背后的概念已经被重新映射了，
I guess, inside my head too
我猜，我头脑里也是这样。
for more industrial applications.
为了更多的工业应用。
My talk again, is really about how we
我的演讲再次强调的是我们如何
can apply NDN and
能够应用NDN并且
those concepts for the next generation
这些概念适用于下一代
of factory automation.
的工厂自动化。
What I would like to highlight mainly is that
我主要想强调的是
the context data mainly
上下文数据主要
evolving on right now,
正在发展中，
it's a context where
正在发展中的情境中，
we are building intelligence and
我们正在构建智能并且~!@#$%^&*()
complex systems in order
我们正在构建智能并且复杂的系统以支持制造业的努力。
to support manufacturing efforts.
为了支持制造业的努力。
Over there, there is a lot
在那边，有很多
of opportunities and the same time,
存在机会同时也有，
a lot of challenges.
面临着许多挑战。
One big challenge that we are
面临的一个重大挑战是
trying to address is to foster
努力解决的问题是要培养
those architecture on having
那些建立在拥有上的架构
a deterministic communication
一种确定性通信
for intelligence C systems.
为智能C系统。
In other words, there is
换句话说，有很多机会。
a lot of opportunities.
有很多机会。
I don't know what happened,
我不知道发生了什么，
I hope that you can still see my screen.
我希望你还能看到我的屏幕。
The point is, the communication over 5G
关键是，5G通信
offers a new opportunity
提供了一个新的机会
that we can leverage,
我们可以利用的，
especially with NDN,
尤其是在NDN（命名数据网络）方面，
mainly from the communication part
主要来自通信部分
of it at the edge,
位于边缘的部分，
going to the applications
应用程序的使用情况
and how we can leverage in
以及我们如何能够利用它来
the end to ensure more resilience
提高韧性。
and more deterministic communication,
以及更加确定性的通信，
leveraging some of its features.
利用它的一些特性。
NDN parallelism, is it
利用它的一些特性，NDN并行性，它是好是坏对于工厂自动化？
good or bad for factory automation?
对于工厂自动化来说是好是坏？
It is still an open question,
这仍然是一个未决的问题，
at least from my side
至少从我的角度来看，
and from Siemens's side,
而从西门子这边来说，
and it's mainly because there are
而这主要是因为存在着
some challenges associated to do that.
一些与此相关的挑战。
First one, it's regarding
首先，它关于
the context and requirements
上下文和要求
or hard real time.
或硬实时。
It's really have requirements
它确实有要求。
that we are pushing,
我们正在推动，
NDN application has been explored
NDN应用已经被探索过了
along those lines, but still,
在这方面，但仍然，
there is no solid or mature effort
在这方面，但仍然没有一个稳固或成熟的努力 that has been supported yet.
that has been supported yet.
这方面还没有得到支持。
The other aspect is mainly
这方面主要是
regarding the protocol supports.
在协议支持方面。
The brown field,
棕色的田野，
it's not something to ignore.
这不是可以忽视的事情。
The brown field is the majority of
棕色地带占据了大多数
the current deployments that are happening.
当前正在进行的部署。
Compliance or interactions with protocols
遵守或与协议的互动
like Fortinet and other Real-Time Protocol,
像Fortinet和其他实时协议，
it is a quite interesting feature
这是一个非常有趣的特性。
that we believe could really
我们相信这真的可以
help the adaptation of
帮助适应
NDN within the factory automation.
工厂自动化中的NDN。
We are aware of some work that
我们知道社区中已经有一些工作
has been done in the community
在社区中已经有一些工作完成
especially for IoT and
特别是针对物联网 (IoT) 和
adaptation to IoT protocols,
适配物联网协议，
but still, it's not hard
但即便如此，它并不难
real-time requirements or at least,
实时要求或至少，
as far as I understand it.
据我所理解。
The second vertically, I would say,
第二个是垂直方向上的，我认为。
it's mainly the model parallelism with IP.
它主要是与IP相关的模型并行性。
It is an assumption.
这是一个假设。
Even if the stack is totally different,
即使技术栈完全不同，
and here I'm referring to
我在这里指的是
standard NDN stack,
标准的NDN堆栈，
still there is an assumption that the
仍然有一个假设认为
IP packet it's more or
IP数据包它更多或者~!@#$%^&*()
less the center of this design.
这个设计的中心较少。
However, some of those real time protocols
然而，一些实时协议
have literally jumped from
已经直接跳跃到
layer 2 to layer 7 on the networking stack.
已经直接跳跃到网络堆栈的第2层到第7层。I think a big question in
I think a big question in
我认为一个重大的问题在于~!@#$%^&*()
my head it's mainly,
我的头主要是，
how we can leverage NDN with those protocols.
我们如何利用NDN与这些协议结合。
Also, real time here.
此外，这是实时的。
This is what I'm showing mainly,
这主要是我展示的内容，
the real-time feature is
实时特性是
this champion term of
这个冠军术语
protocol to enable real-time.
实时启用的协议。
This is something that is
这是某种东西，它是
quite interesting and NDN
相当有趣且是新颖的设计理念
parallelism offers
并行性提供了
something quite unique to look
提供了一种相当独特的东西来观察
at this real time communication
在这种实时通信
on a totally different perspective.
从一个完全不同的角度来看。
Last and not least, sorry first,
最后但同样重要的，首先我要说声抱歉，
for the short or for the low,
为了短期或为了低成本，
I guess, the policy here.
我猜，这里的政策是。
But there are few efforts,
但努力很少，
some of them I have
其中一些我已经直接参与过，
been directly involved on,
直接参与过的，
some others I'm aware
有些其他的我知道
that NIST guys are really pushing
有些其他的我知道，那些NIST的家伙们真的在大力推动，along those lines regarding~!@#$%^&*()
along those lines regarding
~!@#$%^&*()
the evaluation of performance and also,
绩效评估以及，
the investigation of
调查研究
a high-performance stacks like 5G;
高性能的技术栈，比如5G；
what Sloppy and his team are looking at.
Sloppy和他的团队正在研究的东西。
Over there, I think it's really
在那边，我认为它真的是
a nice opportunity that could be leveraged.
一个可以利用的好机会。
In other words, the performance of
换句话说，性能可以
NDN can be enhanced much more.
NDN可以得到更多的增强。
The visualization techniques and
可视化技术和
the acceleration techniques that are
加速技术是借助于
offered by technologies that are used on
所使用的技术提供的
5G or other environment,
5G或其他环境，
that's something that can really
这确实是可以大大促进NDN使用的事情。
boost the use of NDN.
促进NDN的使用。
Again, here I'm referring to some of
再次提到我所指的一些
the high-speed forwarders
高速转发器
that has been explored,
已被探索过的，
that niche or other alternative up-process
已被探索过的那个细分市场或其他替代上游过程，用于使用AI进行转发。
for forwarding using AI.
用于使用AI进行转发。
Again, my main points
再次强调我的主要观点
about this slide is, yes,
关于这张幻灯片，是的。
we are exploring novel architecture
我们正在探索新颖的架构
for factory automation,
为工厂自动化，
and yes, NDN is
为工厂自动化提供了一个非常吸引人的机会
a really intriguing chance
一个非常吸引人的机会
of the parallelism.
的并行性。
However, its application to
然而，将其应用到
real time protocol it's still challenging.
实时协议仍然具有挑战性。
With that, I think
随着那个，我认为
almost less than a couple more minutes left.
几乎不到几分钟了。
I will just mention now that, yes,
我现在要提一下，是的，
please free to contact me.
请随时联系我。
I would love to discuss
我很想讨论
these topics with the community and
这些话题与社区进行讨论，
mainly to figure out how we
主要是为了弄清楚我们如何能够推动这一进程。
can push that forward.
可以推动这一进程。
With that, back to you.
回到你这边。
>> Thanks, Dr. Mahmoudi. We have
>> 谢谢，马哈茂迪博士。我们已经
a minute for any questions
一分钟时间用于任何问题。
[NOISE] within the audience might have.
观众中可能会有的。
Does anybody have any questions?
有人有问题吗？
We can just move the questions to
我们可以把问题转移到
the slack channel [NOISE]
我们可以把问题转移到Slack频道上，[噪音]，也许在最后给大家一分钟时间。
and maybe give everybody a minute at the end.
或许在最后给大家一分钟时间。
Thank you again for the great talk.
谢谢你精彩的演讲。
I have some questions, I'll
我有一些问题，我会
post them on the slack channel.
把它们发布在Slack频道上。
>> Thanks for the opportunity.
>> 谢谢这个机会。
>> Thank you. Let me introduce
>> 谢谢。让我介绍
our next speaker,
我们的下一位演讲嘉宾，
Mr. Jeff White, on
我们的下一位演讲嘉宾，Mr. Jeff White，在
information management in the emerging edge.
信息管理领域的新兴边缘技术。
Jeff leads the autonomous system and
Jeff 领导自主系统和~!@#$%^&*()
edge technical ecosystem development
边缘技术生态系统开发
and composable system,
和可组合系统，
technical strategy initiatives for
技术战略倡议
the Global Chief Technology Officer,
全球首席技术官，
Dell Technologies.
戴尔科技。
He also chairs the
他还担任
Automotive Design Authority Council
汽车设计权威委员会
providing technical leadership
提供技术领导
of Dell's automotive vertical,
戴尔汽车垂直领域，
which is responsible for technical design of
负责技术设计的
automotive enterprise and transformation
汽车企业和转型
solutions. Jeff the floor is yours.
解决方案。Jeff，该你发言了。
>> Thank you, especially to Dr. Mahmoudi for
谢谢你，特别是感谢马哈茂迪博士。
finishing on such a compressed timescale.
在如此紧凑的时间表上完成。
Can everyone see my slides?
大家能看到我的幻灯片吗？
The answer is yes, please let me know if not.
答案是肯定的，请告诉我如果不是。
Jeff White, I work for a Dell Technologies,
我是Jeff White，我在戴尔科技公司工作，
and we're involved in
我们参与了
defining the modern Edge.
定义现代边缘计算。
Moving beyond IoT and
超越物联网并进入到现代计算边缘。
forward into a modern computational Edge.
向前迈进，进入现代计算边缘。
This is our definition that we
这是我们的定义，我们~!@#$%^&*()
put together a year and a half or so ago.
大约一年半前拼凑起来的。
At the core of
在核心的是
any Edge deployment is applications and data.
任何边缘部署的核心是应用程序和数据。
Then, you layer on various layers
然后，您可以叠加各种层次
of orchestration in application management,
来进行应用管理中的编排工作，
ultimately the infrastructure management,
最终进行基础设施管理，
and then,
然后，
of course, we can never forget
当然，我们永远不能忘记
all the devices, sensors, vehicles,
所有设备、传感器、车辆、
and physical capabilities that are required
和所需的物理能力
to build out a modern Edge.
构建一个现代化的边缘网络。
One of the central themes here,
这里的一个核心主题是，
you can see it in almost every
你几乎可以在每一个
line, is data.
你几乎可以在每一行中找到数据。Managing data in the
Managing data in the
你几乎可以在每一行中找到数据。在边缘（Edge）管理数据相当具有挑战性。
Edge is quite challenging.
边缘（Edge）管理相当具有挑战性。
If you think about it,
如果你仔细想想，
Edge is neither On-prem nor in the Cloud,
Edge既不是On-prem（本地部署）也不是在云端，
it is in between.
它介于两者之间。
Data will be transitory to the Edge,
数据将会是临时传输到边缘计算层，
but many functions will be
但是许多功能将会
performed on including ingest,
执行的操作包括摄取，
processing, inference,
处理，推断，
analytics, and the list
分析，以及清单
goes on and on and on.
继续不断地进行着。
But it's moving,
但它在移动着，
it exists as part of a pipeline Edge.
它存在于管道的边缘部分。
Autonomous systems like autonomous vehicles,
像自动驾驶汽车这样的自主系统，
but many more systems that are autonomous,
但还有许多其他的自主系统，
robotic process automation,
机器人流程自动化，
the list will be endless of things that
列表将会无穷无尽，包括了那些……
we embed autonomous technology into.
我们将自主技术嵌入到。
Everything from factory assembly lines,
我们将自主技术嵌入到一切从工厂装配线，
as Dr. Muhammad is familiar with,
正如穆罕默德博士所熟悉的，
to autonomous vehicles, to retail stores,
到自动驾驶汽车，到零售商店，
and controlling certain systems within.
和控制其中的某些系统。
They're going to need to rely on
他们将需要依赖
Edge-based computation and support
边缘计算和支持
for a variety of reasons.
出于各种原因。
The next two are really big.
接下来的两个真的很大。
The assumption that your data is
假设你的数据是
going to be local is not guaranteed
将会是本地的并不是有保证的
for Edge and every
对于 Edge 和每一个
application ever developed,
应用程序开发过程中，
and I know this is a big impact statement,
这是一个重大的影响性声明，
but stick signals of applications ever
但是应用程序的信号粘连情况却始终存在
developed assume that data
开发时假定数据
is either local or it's reachable.
要么是本地的，要么是可以访问的。
Neither one of those assumptions
要么是本地的，要么是可以访问的，这两种假设都非常好，在边缘计算领域。
are very good assumption in Edge.
在边缘计算领域是非常好的假设。
Data's going to be produced
数据将会被生成
by a variety of sensors,
由各种传感器生成，
the Edge may be co-located with it,
边缘可能与它共同定位，
but many times it will not.
但很多时候它不会这样。
The whole purpose of deploying in
部署的整个目的是
Edge is to put
将边缘计算部署的整个目的是为了将共享基础设施部署得更近
shared infrastructure much nearer
共享基础设施部署得更近
the source of data.
数据源头。
Most of the key drivers
大多数关键驱动因素
of Edge relate to data.
的边缘计算主要与数据相关。
Then, if you think about
那么，如果你考虑一下
reachability, you may say,
可达性，你可能会说，
''When we stopped networking,
当我们停止了网络连接，
we got great access networks
我们拥有了优秀的接入网络。
, we have wireless now.''
，我们现在有了无线网络。
All these great things, it's
所有这些了不起的事情，这是
very problematic for Edge,
非常棘手的问题对于边缘计算来说，
if you look at the emerging workloads
如果你关注那些新兴的工作负载
that are driving Edge,
它们正在推动边缘计算发展，
they produce a vast amount of data.
它们产生了大量的数据。
If you think about some of
如果你考虑一些早先的讨论
the talks that were earlier
如果你考虑一些早先的讨论，今天在DARPA周围的讨论，
today around DARPA,
今天在DARPA周围，
if you look at war fighting capabilities,
如果你观察战斗能力，
you look at autonomous vehicles,
如果你观察自动驾驶汽车，
factories, they are
如果你观察工厂，它们是
generating an immense amount of data.
产生大量的数据。
This immense data coupled
产生大量的数据，并且结合了
with access networks of
产生大量的数据，并且结合了接入网络的，不同的带宽将不允许你
varying bandwidth will not allow you to
产生大量的数据，并且结合了接入网络的，不同的带宽将不允许你在所需的时间内达到数据。
reach the data in the timeframes required.
在所需的时间内达到数据。
You can certainly move the data.
您当然可以移动数据。
We worked with customers that
我们与客户合作过，
needed to move five petabytes of
需要移动五PB（petabytes）的
data from North America to Japan.
数据从北美传输到日本。
That's a multi-week process of
这是一个持续数周的过程。
transmitting data even at
传输数据甚至以
10 gigabits per second through a Cloud.
通过云端每秒10吉比特。
If you think about that
如果你考虑一下这个
now moving into the Edge,
现在进入边缘领域，
that is a huge problem.
这是一个巨大的问题。
Actually, it turned out it was easier
实际上，事情变得更简单了。
to load up a storage system and put it on
装载一个存储系统并将其放置在
an airplane than it was to use
比使用飞机还要难
the Internet in the case of reachability.
在可达性方面的互联网。
Think about that applied
考虑将其应用在
to the Edge when you're dealing with
考虑将其应用在边缘计算中，当你处理时
multi hundreds of terabytes and ultimately
数百个TB甚至最终达到
petabytes of data wondering around the Edge.
数百个PB（petabytes）的数据在边缘网络中游荡。
Visibility is also problematic.
能见度也是个问题。
You're not in the Cloud,
你不在云端，
you're not in your end-user location,
你不在最终用户的位置上，
so getting visibility on
所以获取可见性是一个挑战。
this data is a challenge.
这些数据是一个挑战。
Provenance, security,
溯源，安全性，
IP, multicast and unicast.
IP, 多播和单播。
The future of Edge is not a CDN problem,
未来的边缘计算并不是一个CDN问题，
it is a reverse CDN problem.
它是一个反向CDN问题。
You have a vast number of
你有大量的
sources trying to aggregate data
源头试图聚合数据
to ultimately get it to places like
最终将其传送到像这样的地方
the Cloud and core where it can be analyzed.
将其传送到云端和核心，以便进行分析。
The Edge will also include mobile workloads,
边缘计算也将包括移动工作负载，
which is problematic even for NDN,
这即使对于NDN来说也是有问题的，
although there's great ideas around how to
虽然围绕如何有很多好主意，
manage mobility with that.
管理移动性。
But a lot of
但很多
these workloads are going to start
这些工作负载将要开始
to be portable and ultimately mobile.
要具备便携性并最终实现移动性。
IT approaches are not much
IT方法并没有太多优势
better than Internet approaches
比互联网方法更好
to managing the data.
在管理数据方面。
In fact, I would say in many cases
实际上，我会说在很多情况下
they're not as well.
实际上，我会说在很多情况下，他们的状况也不是很好。My boss coined the term polydirectional,
My boss coined the term polydirectional,
我的老板创造了“多向性”这个术语，
which I like because the data's
它能够展示数据的多样性和复杂性，
moving in a lot of different directions,
朝着许多不同的方向移动，
it's not all moving in one direction.
它并非全都朝着一个方向移动。
In current solutions from Cloud,
在当前的云计算解决方案中，
and quite frankly, others,
和坦白说，其他人，
focus on storage as
专注于存储作为
a service analytics, AI enablement.
服务分析，人工智能赋能。
They're not really focused
他们并没有真正集中注意力。
on the problem of,
对于问题，
how do I apply services for governance and
我如何应用服务进行治理和~!@#$%^&*()
how do I apply a movement policy to the data?
如何对数据应用移动策略？
Then lastly,
那么最后，
and I think this is super important.
我认为这非常重要。
If you look at Kubernetes or
如果你看一下Kubernetes或者其他编排框架，比如Mesos，
other orchestration frameworks, Mesos,
其他编排框架，比如Mesos，
the HCI frameworks that Dell sells,
戴尔销售的HCI框架，
very few of them
极少数的
consider data a first-class citizen.
考虑将数据作为一等公民。
Many of the orchestrator frameworks will
许多编排框架将会
make decisions without considering data.
在不考虑数据的情况下做出决策。
They may move the workload,
他们可能会转移工作负载，
but they're not considering reachability.
但他们没有考虑到可达性。
This is a huge problem,
这是一个巨大的问题，
and plugging that into
将其插入到
existing frameworks is not easy to do.
将其插入到现有框架中并不容易。
We've been working in a research project
我们一直在从事一个研究项目。
and we leverage NDN in a significant way.
我们在很大程度上利用了NDN。
It has a lot of different aspects
它有很多不同的方面。
in this research project.
在这个研究项目中。
It is an Edge research project,
这是一个边缘计算研究项目，
but NDN offer some advantages.
但NDN提供了一些优势。
First of all, the data naming
首先，数据命名
capability can provide semantic information,
能力可以提供语义信息，
and location and where the data
和位置以及数据的来源
is invisibility super important.
隐身能力非常重要吗？
If you use a data naming framework
如果您使用数据命名框架
in a "shim" layer that does the application,
在一个“垫片”层中，该层执行应用程序，
that allows the applications
允许应用程序
to interact with the NDN
进行交互
without the applications necessarily
在应用程序不一定需要的情况下
knowing they're interacting with the NDN,
知道他们正在与NDN交互，
can be super helpful,
可以非常有帮助，
and fits very well.
可以非常有帮助，和非常合适。A State Vector Sync is very efficient in
A State Vector Sync is very efficient in
terms of doing distributed 状态向量同步在进行分布式操作方面非常高效。
terms of doing distributed
在进行分布式操作方面
database synchronization,
数据库同步，
and a lot of
以及大量的
these Edge applications will require
这些边缘应用程序将需要
streaming and a continuous
流媒体和持续的
capability to stream and process data.
流媒体和数据处理能力。
State Vector Sync actually,
实际上，状态向量同步，
it's inherent within NDN,
它是NDN内在的，
provides the capability to do that,
提供了这样做的能力，
and if you look at
如果你看看
other more traditional ways
其他更传统的方式
of using Kafka or Flink,
使用Kafka或Flink，
and all these other things
和所有这些其他事情
that are coming out
正在推出的
of the Linux Foundation,
的Linux基金会，
those are all pretty heavyweight.
这些都相当重量级。
They're designed for IT. We've had
他们是为IT设计的。我们已经有过
customers that have turned on Kafka and
客户已经启用了Kafka并且
then Edge environment then
难以应对的边缘计算环境。
had significant challenges because of
面临了重大挑战，因为
the amount of state and
面临了重大挑战，因为它需要的计算资源的数量。
computational resources it requires.
它所需要的计算资源。
Lastly, with NDN,
最后，使用NDN（命名数据网络），
you can integrate with a policy framework
您可以与策略框架集成
the ability to manage a movement policy.
您可以管理移动策略的能力。
If you had capabilities
如果您具备能力
that could classify data and
可以对数据进行分类并且
understand the application framework
理解应用程序框架
and be able to
并且能够
understand the intent of
理解意图
what the data is going to be used for,
数据将被用于什么目的，
you can apply a movement policy.
你可以应用一个移动策略。
If you're in an autonomous vehicle,
如果你在一辆自动驾驶车辆中，
you may have some data that's important,
你可能有一些重要的数据，
yet you may be going through a 5G or
但你可能正在使用5G或者4G链接，并且无法
4G link and it's not possible to
move that terabyte worth of data quickly.
move that terabyte worth
移动那1TB大小
of unstructured data in
的非结构化数据在
any reasonable timeframe at
在任何合理的时间框架内
any reasonable costs through that 5G link.
通过那个5G链接产生的任何合理成本。
But you could cue
但你可以提示
that data so that when you're plugged in
那些数据，这样当你连接上时
at home or when you're
在家里或者当你在外面时候，
recharging your car or whatever,
给你的车充电或者其他什么事情，
and you have a lower cost
和你拥有一个更低的成本
higher bandwidth link
更高带宽的链接
to move that data
移动那些数据
through that may not be metered,
通过那可能不会被计量，
then you could move the data through.
那么你就可以传输数据了。
NDN provides capabilities to do that,
NDN提供了实现这一功能的能力，
not directly within NDN,
而不是直接在NDN内部，
but with a "shim" layer,
而是通过一个"垫片"层，
which we call IML,
我们称之为IML，
that could manage NDN
可以管理NDN
and manage this movement policies,
可以管理这些移动策略，
and then do the advertisement, etc.
然后进行广告宣传等工作。
This is what we're working on.
我们正在做这个工作。
Again, I could talk about it for hours,
再说，我可以谈论几个小时，
but this is just a
但这仅仅是一个
really nice little picture down here about
这里有一幅非常漂亮的小图片，关于
some of the capabilities
我们正在其周围构建的一些功能
that we're building in around it.
我们正在其周围构建的功能。
Of course, Edge is distributed
当然，Edge是分布式的，
across many domains
跨越多个领域
and how to manage that data and
以及如何管理这些数据以及
move it economically is a key component.
经济地移动它是一个关键组成部分。
Wish lists, NDN ideas for the future.
愿望清单，NDN未来的想法。
A lot of the capabilities
很多能力
would be eased if we didn't
如果我们不这样做，就会减轻很多负担
have to do interests flooding
必须做的兴趣泛滥
because many times
因为很多时候
we're going to be moving a single
我们将要移动一个单独的
object or a single file,
我们将要移动一个单独的对象或一个单个文件，
and the ability to send
以及发送的能力
a "ranged" interests without
一种“广泛”的兴趣，无须
having to flood interests
拥有广泛的兴趣
would be very useful.
会非常有用。
We could send one interest and with
我们可以发送一个兴趣点并且通过~!@#$%^&*()
a range of bring all these segments
一系列带回所有这些部分
and it could bring segments back.
并且它可以带回这些部分。
Also, we're thinking about
此外，我们正在考虑
things like using coding
进行编码之类的事情
and where you do
和你在哪里进行
have data that's used in the Edge,
在边缘计算中使用的数据，
partially downloading the file and using
部分下载文件并使用
network coding like CDNs do,
网络编码，就像内容分发网络(CDNs)那样，
where you have a partial file and then when
你有一个部分的文件，然后当
it's used to pull the rest of the data down.
它用于拉取其余的数据。
Having the ability to send
具有发送能力
a "ranged" interests would
涉猎广泛的兴趣会
be very useful
会非常有用
towards a high-performance NFD.
朝着高性能NFD的方向。
One of the reasons I got invited to this,
我被邀请参加这个的原因之一，
we're working within this team
我们正在这个团队内工作。
that is working on high-performance NFD.
正在研究高性能NFD的。
High-performance doesn't
高性能并不一定意味着高带宽，
necessarily mean high bandwidth,
不一定意味着高带宽，
it could mean low latency as well.
它也可能意味着低延迟。
We need lightweight versions
我们需要轻量级版本。
which there are many coming.
将会有许多人来。
I was happy to see
我很高兴见到
the code-based discussion earlier today.
今天早些时候基于代码的讨论。
But we also need the ability to move lots of
但我们也需要能够大量移动
data and not have
数据而不是拥有
a significant penalty for that.
对此将会有严重的惩罚。
Continued development of State Vector Sync,
持续发展状态向量同步，
I think it has great capabilities.
我认为它有很大的潜能。
One of the ideas that we came up with here
我们在这里提出的一个想法是
is Kubernetes as concept of the CSI,
Kubernetes 作为 CSI（Container Storage Interface）的概念，
Container Storage Interface
容器存储接口
where they support
他们支持
storage primitives
存储原语
for different types of capabilities,
针对不同类型的能力，
whether it's AWS,
无论是AWS，
or Adele storage system,
或者是Adele存储系统，
there's a whole list on the internet,
互联网上有一整个列表，
you can look it up.
你可以查一查。
What would be
你可以查一查。一个非常酷的项目是去建造
a really cool project is to build
一个非常酷的项目是去建造
a Container Storage Interface
容器存储接口
directly for NDN with Kubernetes.
直接用于 Kubernetes 的 NDN。
It would be a very
它将是一个非常
interesting thing where you could directly
它将是一个非常有趣的事物，你可以直接
manage from Kubernetes, the NDN environment.
它将是一个非常有趣的事物，你可以直接从Kubernetes管理NDN环境。That was just a crazy idea we had here,
That was just a crazy idea we had here,
这只是我们这里的一个疯狂想法，
but it ultimately
但它最终可能真的很有趣。
could be really interesting.
可能真的很有趣。
This is from my development team,
这是来自我的开发团队，
they wanted to make sure I got it.
他们想确保我收到了。
These are things that
这些是我们在使用时会考虑的事情。
we look at as we've used
我们在使用时会考虑的事情
NDN in our research environment
NDN在我们的研究环境中
and our test environments.
和我们的测试环境。
Improved network deployment tools.
改进的网络部署工具。
If we have to set up complex topologies
如果我们必须建立复杂的网络拓扑结构
which you may see an Edge and elsewhere,
你可能会在Edge和其他地方看到它，
it's pretty error prone to set those up.
设置它们相当容易出错。
It's not very user-friendly.
它不是很用户友好。
Observability is a bit of a challenge,
可观察性有点挑战性，
NDN uses a quite old school approach.
NDN采用了一种相当老派的方法。
Most folks are using Prometheus today.
大多数人今天都在使用Prometheus。
If we had integration with that,
如果我们能与之集成，
be able to look at metrics through NDN,
如果我们能与之集成，能够通过NDN查看指标，
would actually be in
实际上会在一个可观测的框架中。
a single observable framework.
在一个单一的可观测框架中。
You can look at Prometheus style
你可以看一下普罗米修斯风格
online and see what it does.
在线上查看它的功能。
Then, formal plug-in architecture.
然后是正式的插件架构。
There's a lot of really cool tools,
有许多非常酷的工具，
NDN trace, the list goes on and on and on.
NDN追踪，这个列表还在持续增长。
They're all managed separately
它们都是分开管理的。
outside of NFD.
它们都是在NFD之外分开管理的。
If you can have a formal plug-in framework,
如果你能有一个正式的插件框架，
then people would be able to build
那么人们就能够构建
their own tools and then integrate
自己的工具，然后集成
that into NFD without
that into NFD without 的工具，然后集成，having to do a lot of custom development.
having to do a lot of custom development.
需要进行大量的定制开发。
It will make it a lot more modern looking.
它会使其看起来更加现代。
Of course, NFD is a high performance.
当然，NFD是高性能的。
It's the heart of how NDN works.
它是NDN工作方式的核心。
You have to balance that with
你必须在此基础上保持平衡，
the risk of making NFD less stable.
承担使NFD变得不稳定的风险。
These are wish list things
这些是愿望清单上的事项。
we want to share with the community and
我们想要与社区分享的是
some of the things we found is we
我们发现的一些事情是我们
continue to do our development
继续进行我们的开发工作。
and research around Edge.
和围绕边缘计算的研究。
>> Thank you. That is
谢谢。那是
really nice presentation that has
非常精彩的演讲，它有
a lot of interesting pointers.
很多有趣的要点。
We'll move the discussion to the Slack.
我们会将讨论转移到Slack上。
The next presenter, Junxiao.
下一位报告人，Junxiao。
Junxiao Shi is going to present
Junxiao Shi 将要进行报告。
NDNts video
NDNts视频
streaming using QUIC and WebTransport.
使用QUIC和WebTransport进行流媒体传输。
Junxiao is a guest researcher at NIST.
Junxiao 是 NIST 的一名客座研究员。
He's a core NDN developer
他是一个核心的NDN开发者。
and has been developing
并且一直在开发
NDN network for a while since 2013.
自2013年以来一直在研究NDN网络。
Also enjoys building websites and
还喜欢构建网站和
browsers based NDN applications.
基于浏览器的NDN应用程序。
Junxiao, go ahead.
俊霄，请继续。
>> Hi, this is Junxiao. I'm presenting.
嗨，我是俊霄。我正在介绍。
This one is my personal project of
这是我的个人项目
NDNts video streaming
NDNts视频流媒体
using QUIC and WebTransport.
使用QUIC和WebTransport。
>> Junxiao, can you increase
>> 俊晓，你能增加
the volume from your side it's a little low.
你那边的音量有点小。
I think it could be okay.
我觉得应该可以。
I think it should be. Go ahead.
我觉得应该可以。继续吧。
>> Yes. I'm Junxiao.
>> 是的。我是俊霄。
This is my personal project,
这是我的个人项目，
NDNts video streaming using
使用NDNts进行视频流传输
QUIC and WebTransport [NOISE].
QUIC和WebTransport [噪音]。
NDNts video is a website.
NDNts视频是一个网站。
It's a web application that performs
它是一个执行操作的网络应用程序。
pre-recorded video
预录制视频
streaming over the NDN network.
在NDN网络上进行流媒体传输。
I started developing this website
我开始开发这个网站
in parallel with iViSA which is
与iViSA并行的是
a paper in ICN 20 to test
一篇在ICN 20上测试的论文
NDNts congestion controls or
NDNts拥塞控制或者
congestion control in my library.
我的库中的拥塞控制。
Both NDNts video and iViSA uses
Both NDNts video and iViSA use the same streaming library which is我的库中的拥塞控制。
the Shaka Player and the Shaka Packager.
Shaka Player和Shaka Packager。
Since Black Friday 2020,
自2020年黑色星期五以来，
I started publishing my own content because I
我开始发布自己的内容是因为我
believe it's content that
相信是内容本身吸引了观众，而不是技术。
attracts viewers, not the technology.
吸引观众的是内容本身，而不是技术。
Viewer doesn't really care
观众其实并不在乎
whether it's NDN or not,
观众其实并不在乎，是否是NDN。
so I have the content.
所以我有内容了。
My content is encoded in
所以我的内容是以编码形式存在的。
the DASH format with
DASH格式支持
four resolutions up to 720p.
四种分辨率，高达720p。
Earlier this year I experimented
今年早些时候我进行了实验
with QuicTransport in the Chrome browser
在Chrome浏览器中使用QuicTransport
and this talk is
这个演讲是
mainly a report of this experiment.
这个演讲主要是对这个实验的报告。
Why do we want to use QUIC?
我们为什么要使用QUIC？
Traditionally, web applications in
传统上，网络应用程序在
NDN connect to
与NDN连接
the NDN network through WebSockets.
通过WebSockets连接NDN网络。
NFD is a forwarding software
NFD是一种转发软件。
itself, supports WebSocket.
它本身支持WebSocket。
There are other global NDN testbeds there
全球还有其他的NDN测试平台。
is nginx reverse proxies software that
是一个Nginx反向代理软件，它……
exposed NFD WebSocket over
暴露了NFD WebSocket 连接
HTTPS so that browsers
HTTPS以便浏览器
can see could it connect with.
可以看到它是否能够连接。
But a problem is I'm
但问题是我
developing congestion control and
开发拥塞控制和
other NDN library also
其他NDN库也已经开始有拥塞控制。
has started to have congestion control.
已经开始有拥塞控制。
The congestion control algorithm is more or
拥塞控制算法更多地是
less derived from TCP,
与TCP关系不大，
so it's a TCP-like a congestion control.
所以这是类似于TCP的拥塞控制。
But WebSocket protocol itself rests over TCP.
但是WebSocket协议本身是基于TCP之上的。
While we have NDN congestion control,
虽然我们有NDN拥塞控制，
TCP-like and also WebSocket over TCP,
类似TCP以及基于TCP的WebSocket，
this is effective running
这是有效运行
TCP congestion control over
TCP拥塞控制机制
TCP and a TCP over
TCP和TCP之上
TCP is known to lead to
TCP被认为会导致
better performance and other misbehaviors.
更好的性能和其他不当行为。
Therefore, QUIC is different
因此，QUIC是不同的
because QUIC itself rests over UDP.
因为QUIC本身是建立在UDP之上的。
In particular, Quictransport API it provides
特别是，QuicTransport API它提供了
unreliable datagram service just like UDP.
不可靠的数据报服务，就像UDP一样。
The difference from plain UDP
与普通UDP的区别
is that it is encrypted and
它是加密的
authenticated to fulfill the web-trans model
认证以满足Web传输模型需求
and effective the hosting is
以及托管的有效性
UDP all the way and therefore
UDP一直到底，因此
our consumer side of
我们的消费者端
TCP-like congestion control can work well.
TCP类似的拥塞控制可以工作得很好。
But a lot of people don't
但是很多人不会
support QUIC therefore,
支持QUIC，因此，
I built NDN-QUIC gateway with
我构建了支持NDN-QUIC的网关，借助
aioquic and python-ndn libraries.
我构建了支持NDN-QUIC的网关，借助aioquic和python-ndn库。网关作为一个代理
The gateway serves as a proxy
网关作为一个代理
between QUIC and a plain UDP.
在QUIC和普通UDP之间。
Each QUIC connection becomes
每个QUIC连接成为
a UDP face on the local NFD.
一个在本地NFD上的UDP接口。
Local NFD on the same machine as a gateway,
作为网关在同一台机器上的本地NFD，
it can provide forwading and
它可以提供转发和
caching into the wider NDN network.
缓存进入更广泛的NDN网络中。
This is how I deployed
这就是我部署的方式。
NDN-QUIC during the experiment.
实验中使用的NDN-QUIC。
On the testbed I deployed
在我部署的测试环境中
the two replicas of my NDNts-videos-servers,
在我部署的测试环境中，我的NDNts-videos-servers的两个副本，they serve the same content of ram Buffalo
they serve the same content of ram Buffalo
他们提供相同的ram Buffalo内容。
in New York, and Tokyo, Japan.
在纽约和日本东京。
Then I deploy the three instance
然后我部署了三个实例
of NDN-QUIC gateway located in Amsterdam,
的NDN-QUIC网关位于阿姆斯特丹，
Los Angeles, and Tokyo.
洛杉矶和东京。
They all connect to
它们都连接到
the testbed and each gateway has
它们都连接到测试床和每个网关都有
a local NFD with
它们都连接到测试床和每个网关都有一个本地NFD，具有高达98,000个参与者的缓存容量。
a cache capacity up to 98,000 entrants.
具有高达98,000个参与者的缓存容量。
The viewers in different continents they are
观众们分布在不同的大陆上。
directed to connect to
连接到
a nearby NDN-QUIC gateway.
附近的NDN-QUIC网关。
This is a static assignment.
这是一个静态分配。
If the user is not using Chrome browser,
如果用户没有使用Chrome浏览器，
since only chrome support QUIC or
既然只有Chrome支持QUIC，或者
if the user cannot connect to QUIC,
如果用户无法连接到QUIC，
that they will still connect to
他们仍将连接到
the testbed over Websocket as usual.
他们仍将通过Websocket连接到测试平台，像往常一样。
I also have HTTP
我也有HTTP。
beacon servers that can collect
可以收集数据的信标服务器
a video quality of
视频质量
experience metrics
体验指标
using navigator send Beacon API.
使用 Navigator 发送 Beacon API。
What is my content?
~!@#$%^&*()
My content is my push-up videos.
我的内容是我的俯卧撑视频。
I made this website and
我制作了这个网站并且
put my content on there and then I
我把我的内容放在那儿然后我
posted a link to
发布了一个链接到
LowEndTalk and LowEndSpirit forums.
LowEndTalk和LowEndSpirit论坛。
Those push up will soon become
这些俯卧撑很快就会变成~!@#$%^&*()
a meme in the forum because
因为这些俯卧撑很快就会变成~!@#$%^&*(), 在论坛上已经成为了一个梗，其他用户也在谈论它。
other users are also talking about it.
其他用户也在谈论它。
Those forum members, they will
那些论坛成员，他们会
click and watch my push-ups.
点击并观看我的俯卧撑。
The benefit for me is I get
我得到的好处是我得到了
real-world usage statistics
现实世界使用统计数据
of my application.
的应用程序。
During the 32 days of data collection period,
在32天的数据收集期间，
I received 541 viewers from
在32天的数据收集期间，我收到了来自六大洲的541位观众，他们代表着
six continents and that they represent
六大洲，他们代表着
a total of 6.4 hours of playback time.
总共有6.4小时的播放时间。
This is uncontrolled experiment
这是一个不受控制的实验。
but I believe my method is more
但我相信我的方法更加
realistic than iViSA because iViSA they
的方法更加现实，因为iViSA他们~!@#$%^&*()
run emulated the viewers
模拟了观众的运行情况
in Amazon Web Service,
在亚马逊网络服务中，
but the real viewers don't have as
但真正的观众并没有那么多
good data center quality network connections.
优质的数据中心网络连接。
This diagram shows video resolution
该图表显示了视频分辨率。
that according to my statistics,
根据我的统计数据，
the brown bars are from
棕色条形来自于
WebSocket connection and the purple bars
WebSocket连接和紫色条形
are from QUIC connections.
来自QUIC连接。
The darker shade,
更深的阴影色调，
that means higher resolution.
这意味着更高的分辨率。
As we can see in Europe
我们可以看到在欧洲
when a user is connected over WebSocket,
当用户通过WebSocket连接时，
42 percent of the time they are
他们有42%的时间是这样的
playing at the highest resolution,
在最高分辨率下播放时，
but when they are connected over
但是当它们通过连接时
QUIC 60 percent of the time they are
QUIC在60%的时间里会
playing at the highest resolution which
播放最高分辨率的视频时，哪个
means QUIC
在播放最高分辨率的视频时，QUIC提供了视频分辨率的提升。
provides improvement in video resolution.
提供了视频分辨率的提升。
We also see the similar improvements in
我们也看到了类似的改进在
Asia and North America
亚洲和北美洲
but to a smaller extent.
但程度较小。
I also attract as a startup delay,
我也吸引了作为启动延迟，
which is duration between
持续的时间在……之间
the user press the Start button
用户按下开始按钮。
until they can see my awesome push-ups.
直到他们能看到我那惊人的俯卧撑。
Since it's tracked separately
既然它被单独追踪
for Europe and North America
对于欧洲和北美
and Asia and we can see that
在亚洲，我们可以看到
in both Europe and Asia,
在欧洲和亚洲 both
we see a startup daily
我们每天都看到一家初创公司。
decreased up by more than 1.5 seconds.
减少了超过1.5秒。
In North America, this decrease
在北美，这种减少
is 500 milliseconds.
是500毫秒。
Since I start to experiment in February and
自从我二月份开始实验以来，
March this year I'm keep
三月份我一直在~!@#$%^&*()
improving NDNts video application.
改善NDNts视频应用程序。
First, in the Chrome browser.
首先，在Chrome浏览器中。
Chrome browsers, they decided to
他们决定在Chrome浏览器中，
replace a QuicTransport with WebTransport.
他们决定在Chrome浏览器中，替换QuicTransport为WebTransport。The difference is that it uses HTTPS/3 for
The difference is that it uses HTTPS/3 for
它的不同之处在于它使用了HTTPS/3来
better [inaudible] but it's
更好的[听不清楚]但它是~!@#$%^&*()
still the same datagram service.
依旧是同样的数据报服务。
Original trial of WebTransport just ended
WebTransport 的原始试验刚刚结束
so we cannot use
所以我们现在无法使用
WebTransport or QUIC right now,
所以我们现在无法使用WebTransport或QUIC，
but it's scheduled to be shipping in Chrome
但它计划将在Chrome中发布。
97 released early next year.
97将在明年初发布。
I hope the global NDN testbed
我希望全球NDN测试平台
can support WebTransport at the time.
可以在那时支持WebTransport。
I'm also building ndn6,
我也在构建ndn6，
my own global scale NDN network.
我自己的全球规模的NDN网络。
It currently has nine routers
它目前有九台路由器。
with peering with the testbed.
它与测试床建立了对等连接。
It supports WebTransport on most locations.
它在大多数地方支持WebTransport。
I have already moved
我已经搬家了。
my video producers there,
我的视频制作人在那里，
but I'm still improving this setup.
但我仍在完善这个设置。
Here are some links so
以下是一些链接，以便
that you can read later
以便您稍后阅读。
more about these experiments. Thank you.
更多关于这些实验的信息。谢谢。
>> Thank you,
谢谢您，
Junxiao. Really interesting presentation.
俊霄，真是一次有趣的演讲。
Again, for those
再次，对于那些
of you who have any queries,
对于那些有任何疑问的你们，
I'm sure you have many questions to Junxiao.
我相信你们对于俊晓有很多问题。
Please use the Slack channel for comments.
请使用Slack频道进行评论。
I will move to the next presentation,
我将继续进行下一个演讲，
which is NDN play by Varun Patil from UCLA.
这是由加州大学洛杉矶分校的Varun Patil 所表演的NDN戏剧。
Varun is a graduate student in
Varun是加州大学洛杉矶分校的研究生，
the Computer Science Department at UCLA,
Varun是加州大学洛杉矶分校计算机科学系的研究生，他的研究兴趣在于系统和
his research interests are in systems and
他的研究兴趣在于系统和
data-centric networking and is
他的研究兴趣在于系统和数据中心网络，并且目前正在研究NDN同步协议。
currently working on NDN sync protocols.
目前正在研究NDN同步协议。
Thank you, Varun. Please go ahead and share.
谢谢你，Varun。请继续分享。
>> Thank you, Jay
谢谢你，Jay。
Can you see my screen?
你能看到我的屏幕吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Great. I'm going
>> 太好了。我正准备去
to be giving a live demo of NDN Play,
即将现场演示 NDN Play，
which is a browser-based
基于浏览器的
NDN visualizer and simulator.
NDN 可视化和仿真器。
But let me just first have a couple of
但是让我先说几句
slides here just to give us some things.
这里有一些幻灯片，给我们一些资料。
First, thing is why did we build this thing?
首先，我们为什么要建造这个东西？
What is the motivation behind it?
它背后的动机是什么？
As was the theme of the first panel
第一个小组讨论的主题是什么？
today and what Peter said,
今天以及彼得所说的内容。
that getting started with NDN is not easy.
开始使用NDN并不容易。
Newcomer might ask, where do I start?
新手可能会问，我该从哪里开始？
For example, just to run the first line
例如，仅仅运行第一行代码
of code for someone new to NDN,
对于刚接触NDN的新手来说，
they have to do a lot of things
他们必须做很多事情。
like get NDN Cxx
They must do a lot of things, like get NDN Cxx, then setup NFD on ~!@#$%^&*().
then setup NFD on
然后在~!@#$%^&*()上设置NFD
their local machine and
他们的本地计算机上
then write the C++ code,
然后编写C++代码，
compile it and run it.
编译并运行它。
It's a lot of things that they need to do
他们需要做很多事情。
before they can write
在他们能写下
their first line of code.
在他们能写下他们的第一行代码之前。
The second thing is that
在他们能写下他们的第一行代码之前，视觉演示很有帮助。
visual demonstrations are nice
视觉演示很有帮助。
no matter whether you are a new
无论你是新手
or whether you're an expert on NDN,
或者你是NDN方面的专家，
looking at things always makes more sense.
观察事物总是更有意义。
Finally, it's the flip side of
终于，它是事物的另一面
the first one that we
我们第一个~!@#$%^&*()
also need tools to showcase NDN to newcomers.
也需要工具来向新来者展示NDN。
For example, students or people
例如，学生或者人们
who don't really know that
可能不太了解网络方面的知识，
if we had tools that we could show
如果我们有可以展示的工具，
them as something about NDN,
它们与NDN有关，
then that would be great.
那就太好了。
That's why I built NDN-Play,
这就是为什么我建立了NDN-Play，
which is a playground for NDN that
这是一个用于NDN的游乐场，完全在浏览器中运行。
runs completely in the browser.
完全在浏览器中运行。
It's serverless.
它是无服务器的。
It's deployed on GitHub pages
它部署在GitHub页面上。
and the link is below,
链接在下面。
you can just open it if you want to.
如果你想的话，你可以直接打开它。
It's play.ndn.today.
它是 play.ndn.today。
The NDN Play simulates an NDN network in
NDN Play模拟了一个NDN网络在
the browser and it
的浏览器中，并且它
has some visualizations in it.
在它里面有一些可视化元素。
Of course, it's open source and
当然，它是开源的并且
there are examples available.
当然，它是开源的并且有示例可供参考。
Some features of NDN-Play are that it
NDN-Play 的一些特点是它
obviously has a visual
显然具有可视化特性。
topology editor pretty standard.
拓扑编辑器相当标准。
It can also export the topology to mini NDN,
它还可以将拓扑导出到mini NDN，
where you can run real experiments
在那里你可以运行真实的实验
with a real NDN code.
使用真实的NDN代码。
It simulates
它模拟
NDN network, as I mentioned earlier.
它模拟NDN网络，正如我之前提到的。
It can also run NDNts code in the browser,
它还能在浏览器中运行NDNts代码，
which I will demonstrate.
我将会进行演示。
You can actually run simple NDN experiments
您实际上可以运行简单的NDN实验。
right in the browser
直接在浏览器中
without setting up anything.
无需设置任何东西。
Along with that, you can capture
此外，你还可以捕获
the traffic that goes along in
通过的交通流量
the simulation and you can visualize
模拟和你可以可视化
this traffic and you
这个交通和你
can see what is going where,
可以看到谁在往哪里去，
and you can also look into the traffic,
并且你还可以查看交通情况，
what the TLVs are.
TLVs是什么。
Again, I'll demonstrate this.
再次，我将演示这个。
Just a quick note before I
在我开始之前，我想快速说明一下
start the real demo,
开始真正的演示，
that ongoing work is in
正在进行的工作是在
integration of this NDN Play
正在进行的工作是在集成这个NDN Play，
with mini NDN where we
与迷你NDN一起，我们可以看到数据包在它们周围流动。
can see the packets flowing around as they
可以看到数据包在它们周围流动。
actually get around in the back-end
实际上可以在后端环境中进行操作。
of mini NDN and we can
实际上可以在后端环境中进行操作的mini NDN，我们可以在运行时动态地更改拓扑。
also change the topology on the fly,
也可以动态地更改拓扑，
git status repos graphs on.
Git状态仓库图表开启。
Also there's a plan to have
还有一个计划是要有
security visualization
安全可视化
and some template experiments,
和一些模板实验，
so new people can
以便新人可以
just click a button and then
只需点击一个按钮然后
run some experiments that we defined earlier.
我们之前定义的一些实验。
Now, I'll go to the Demo.
现在，我将去演示。
This is the NDN-Play user interface.
这是NDN-Play用户界面。
But the first thing that you see is
但你首先看到的是
the network topology.
网络拓扑。
You can just add some nodes here or you
你可以在这里添加一些节点或者你
can connect them up, pretty standard.
你可以将它们连接起来，这是很标准的操作。
So, as soon as you
所以，一旦你
create a new node or you have a topology,
创建一个新节点或者你有一个拓扑图，
then NDN-Play will start up
然后NDN-Play将会启动
assimilated forward on each of these.
每一个都进行了同化前向处理。
It's not a real forward like NFP,
它不像NFP那样是真正的前向处理，
but it's something basic that works.
但它是一些基本但有效的东西。
But it should get the basic stuff done.
但它应该能完成基本的工作。
Now what I'm going to do is
现在我要做的是
that I'm going to
我要做的是
select a node, let's say this one.
选择一个节点，比如这个。
There are some examples on
有一些例子在 ~!@#$%^&*()
the GitHub that I'm going to
我即将要去的GitHub
just copy over here for sake of time.
只是为了节省时间而复制过来。
I'll just take a simple
我只是简单地
producer-consumer example.
生产者-消费者示例。
I go to the editor, I put in.
我进入编辑器，我输入。
The editor also has syntax completion.
编辑器还具有语法补全功能。
I just put on a simple piece of code.
我刚刚写了一段简单的代码。
This node here c is going to produce data on
这个节点c将要生产数据在
the name NDN producer test
NDN生产者测试的名称
and the data is going to be
和数据将会是
hello from NDN producer.
你好，来自NDN生产者。
It's just a few lines of code
这只是几行代码
that resists a piece of data.
它抵抗了一条数据。
Then I run this code on this node.
然后我在这个节点上运行这段代码。
Now, if you just notice then it
如果你刚刚注意到的话，那么它~!@#$%^&*()
registered new preface on
注册了新的前言在
the local forwarder on that node.
在那个节点上的本地转发器。
Now, I'll take the other piece of code,
现在，我将取另一段代码，
which is the consumer, go to
去找消费者，
a different node and put it in there.
去找一个不同的节点并将其放置进去。
Now this code is
现在这段代码是
just sending an interest for the data that we
刚刚发送了我们对数据的兴趣
produced on the other node
在另一个节点上生成
and then it'll just say what data is.
然后它将会说明什么是数据。
Then you can come back
然后你可以回来
here and run the code,
然后在这里运行代码，
so it'll fetch the data
然后它会获取数据
and it just run the code.
然后它就会运行代码。
The simple example may not seem like much,
这个简单的例子可能看起来不怎么样，
but if you notice,
但如果你仔细观察，
I just ran real actual NDN code in
我刚刚真正运行了实际的NDN代码在
a browser without actually installing
一个浏览器而不需要实际安装
NFD or any library like that.
NFD或者类似的库。
It just makes life easier that way.
这样会让生活变得更轻松。
Now one more thing is that I
现在还有一件事就是我
mentioned that we had
提到我们有
Packet Capture and visualization.
数据包捕获和可视化。
I can take any intermediate node
我可以选择任何中间节点
and I go to the Packet Capture,
并且我前往数据包捕获处，
I see all of the packets
我看到了所有的数据包
that have gone through this note,
已经通过这个节点的，
and I can click on them to
并且我可以点击它们来
examine the actual TLV content of the packet.
检查数据包的实际TLV内容。
One last thing is that when I run
最后一件事是当我运行时
this experiment now I can just dump it
这个实验现在我可以直接将它导出
to a file and share it with someone else,
以便将文件分享给其他人，
so they can just load the file
以便他们可以直接加载文件
and view the results for themselves.
并亲自查看结果。
I also mentioned that there is
我还提到有
mini NDN integration that is in progress.
正在进行中的迷你NDN集成。
I will actually load an experiment that
我将实际上载入一个实验，
I ran some time earlier that
我早些时候运行了一段时间
was actually running mini NDN
实际上运行的是迷你NDN
and now it is imported in NDN-Play.
现在它已经被导入到NDN-Play中。
This experiment actually run C++ code
这个实验实际上运行了C++代码。
and you can see
您可以看到
all the packet traces in the browser itself.
所有的数据包跟踪都在浏览器本身中。
I can share this file with
我可以与他人共享这个文件
anyone and they can
任何人都可以
examine what the experience I had like.
审视我所经历的是什么样的体验。
I can examine the TLV inside
我可以检查内部的TLV。
the packets individualist and something like
数据包的个体主义者和类似的东西
that and can also replay what
那个也能重放什么
traffic actually flowed in the nitrile
交通实际上在丁腈中流动。
during the time of the experiment.
在实验期间。
It can help you
它可以帮助你
identify hotspots or something like
识别热点或类似的东西
that or maybe figure
那或者也许是弄清楚
out where traffic is going,
弄清楚交通往哪里去，
where is it not going.
它没有去哪里。
I guess that's all for my demo.
我猜我的演示就到这里吧。
>> Thank you, Varun.
>> 谢谢你，Varun。
We have a few minutes if
我们还有几分钟时间如果
anybody has any questions on this.
有人对此有疑问吗？
Well, since we have time,
既然我们有时间，
let me ask you one quick question.
让我快速问你一个问题。
In the context of this,
在这个情境下，
is there a way we could connect
在这个情境下，我们是否有办法能够建立连接，your NDN-Play with something like NDN SIM for
your NDN-Play with something like NDN SIM for
在这个情境下，我们是否有办法能够建立连接，将你的NDN-Play与类似NDN SIM这样的东西结合起来，
new programmers to be able
让新程序员能够
to build topologies on
构建拓扑结构在
NDN-Play and then connected back to
NDN-Play 然后重新连接回去
the simulator, is that [inaudible]
模拟器，那是[听不清]。
>> NDN SIM is not something that I've used,
NDN SIM是我还没有使用过的东西，
so I've not worked with yet,
我还没有使用过的东西，
but similar is what
但是类似的是什么？
I'm working on with mini NDN.
我正在使用mini NDN工作。
We just connected to mini
我们刚刚连接到了mini
NDN and I can create
NDN和我可以创造
a topology on the Phi,
一个在Phi上的拓扑结构，
then the topology gets built in mini NDN,
然后在mini NDN中构建了拓扑结构，
then you can run real C++ code there
然后你可以在那里运行真实的C++代码。
or any language code in mini NDN.
或者在mini NDN中运行任何语言的代码。
>> This is very cool for somebody who's new.
这对新手来说非常酷。
They can actually just built
他们实际上可以仅仅构建~!@#$%^&*()
the topology using a visual programming.
他们实际上可以仅仅使用视觉编程来构建拓扑。
>> Exactly. That's the intention.
确实如此。这就是意图。
Also in the future, the
未来也将会如此。
last one that I mentioned
上一个我提到的
that I wanted to
我想要
have a set of template experiments,
有一套模板实验，
so you can actually run
因此你实际上可以运行
the sync on three or four notes
同步三个或四个音符
in the browser itself and it still works,
在浏览器本身中也同样有效。
so some experiment like that
因此有些实验就是这样进行的。
where user can come in
用户可以进入的地方
and run it and see what's happening in NDN.
并运行它，观察在NDN中发生了什么。
>> Now, we can actually use these
现在，我们实际上可以使用这些
for assignments
来完成作业
and computer networks classes.
和计算机网络课程。
But I guess could be browser.
但我猜可能是浏览器的问题。
That's good. Thank you.
这很好。谢谢你。
Does anybody else have any questions?
还有其他人有问题吗？
Let's move to our next speaker.
让我们转向下一位发言人。
Amar [inaudible].
~!@#$%^&*()
His presentation is Multiverse;
他的演讲主题是多元宇宙；
designing a network management system NDN.
设计一个网络管理系统NDN。
Amar did his PhD
Amar 完成了他的博士学位。
on limited networking in IoT.
他目前在NIST，我猜，研究物联网中的有限网络问题。
He's currently, I guess NIST,
他目前在NIST，我猜，
working on the Multiverse research platform
他目前在NIST，我猜，在Multiverse研究平台工作，用于网络管理。
for network management. Please go ahead now.
用于网络管理。请现在继续。
>> Thank you. Multiverse is
>> 谢谢。Multiverse是
a research platform we develop at
我们在开发的一项研究平台
NIST to
国家标准与技术研究院
experiment with network management systems.
今天，我将展示我们如何实验网络管理系统。
Today, I'm presenting how we
experiment with the network management system and intend to incorporate Named Data Networking (NDN) into our design.
use and plan to use NDN in our design.
使用并计划在我们的设计中采用NDN。
Multiverse provides centralized
Multiverse 提供了集中化的
management network with
管理网络与
a web based controller
基于网络的控制器
and agents deployed on network elements.
和部署在网络元素上的代理。
We currently work with
我们目前与~!@#$%^&*()
three types of network technologies.
三种类型的网络技术。
There is NDN networks
有NDN网络
with NDN-DPDK forwarder,
配合NDN-DPDK转发器，
which we are also developing our group.
我们的团队也在开发中。
We play with IP networks with Sonic NOS,
我们使用Sonic NOS来进行IP网络的实验。
deployed in our lab and we recently started
部署在我们的实验室中，我们最近开始了
optical path provisioning service
光路配置服务
for quantum network management.
用于量子网络管理。
These three technologies need
这三项技术需要
common services such as telemetry,
遥测等公共服务，
which we build as a shared platform
我们构建的作为一个共享平台
for the three management.
对于三个管理层面。
But currently these network technologies
但目前这些网络技术
have different features and complexity
具有不同的特点和复杂性。
and have
并且具有
different configuration expectations.
不同的配置期望。
But they may require
但他们可能需要
different management approaches,
不同的管理方法，
which may threaten the consistency
可能会威胁到一致性
of the Multiverse platform.
多元宇宙平台。
For sake of time,
为了节省时间，
I cannot go into
我无法进入~!@#$%^&*()
the details of the difference,
但这是差异细节的快速总结，
the requirement and features.
要求和特性。
Multiverse includes two researcher areas.
多元宇宙包括两个研究领域。
One is network intelligence,
一个是网络智能，
which consists on building
由构建组成
a Digital Twin service with
一个数字孪生服务，具有
a single network model
一个单一网络模型
for the three networks.
对于这三个网络。
We use it for error detection
我们用它来检测错误。
and configuration validations.
和配置验证。
The second one which we're interested
我们感兴趣的是第二个。
in today is the Network Management API.
今天我们要讨论的是网络管理API。
We try to find a balance between
我们试图找到一个平衡点
quick prototyping with IP and
快速原型制作结合IP使用和
deployment which we use IP
我们使用的部署方式结合了IP使用，
and also innovative management schemas
以及创新的管理模式
we want to experiment with NDN.
我们想尝试使用NDN。
We also want to reuse
我们也想要复用
what we learned as much as possible.
我们尽可能地学习了。
For that we design pub/sub abstraction,
为此，我们设计了发布/订阅抽象层，
which is independent of IP and NDN
它独立于IP和NDN。
to design our network management APIs.
来设计我们的网络管理API。
I illustrate how we envision
我展示了我们如何构想
this abstraction
这种抽象
with quantum network management.
我们考虑使用NDN进行量子网络管理。
We consider using NDN
我们考虑使用NDN
to experiment with quantum
进行量子实验
network management,
网络管理，
because it's simple enough and
因为它足够简单，而且
we can start integrating
我们可以开始集成
NDN from the beginning
我们可以从头开始NDN。
of the pollution design.
的污染设计。
Basically,
基本上，
a quantum experiment happens between
一个量子实验发生在
two experiment sides and an
两个实验方面和一个
application user which is usually run by
应用程序用户通常由~!@#$%^&*()
a scientist requests
一位科学家请求
a path setup from the controller,
一条从控制器设置的路径，
which computes the path and sends commands
计算路径并发送命令
to switches to configure cross connects.
以配置交叉连接的开关。
Then the path can be maintained,
然后路径可以维护，
it can be renewed as needed by the user.
用户可以根据需要对其进行更新。
For this, we design
为此，我们设计了~!@#$%^&*()
a simple management API using pub/sub.
为此，我们设计了一个简单的管理API，使用发布/订阅模式。
To provide the path scheduling service,
为了提供路径调度服务，
we have our three entities that share
我们有三个实体共享
a couple of topics through publish-subscribe.
我们通过发布-订阅机制共享了一些话题。
The application
应用程序
publishes a request for a path,
发布路径请求，
and the controller receives
控制器接收
the request and computes the path and
请求并计算路径和
starts configuring these which
开始配置这些，哪些
is by sending commands and receiving reports.
通过发送命令和接收报告来实现。
It's a very simple API for this service.
这个服务的API非常简单。
But then we can define
但是我们可以定义
a high level description of this API that
一个高级别的描述，这个API它
contains both the communication
包含了通信两方面的内容
aspects with topics,
涉及主题的方面，
message formats, and pub/sub operations,
消息格式，以及发布/订阅操作，
and the security aspects
及安全方面
with trust and access control.
与信任和访问控制相关。
There is
需要
an existing specification initiative for
现有的规范倡议
pub/sub API called AsyncAPI
发布/订阅 API 称为 AsyncAPI
in spiked from OpenAPI.
受到 OpenAPI 的启发。
As an example, I represented a small part of
作为一个例子，我展示了一小部分
the path scheduling API we
我们的路径调度API是按照AsyncAPI方法设计的。
designed using the AsyncAPI approach.
使用AsyncAPI方法设计。
We see the semantics look very familiar
我们看到这些语义看起来非常熟悉。
to NDN and non-NDN people which
对于了解NDN和不了解NDN的人来说，这是一个很好的开始方式。
is a good way to start with NDN for IP
对于了解IP的人来说，这是开始学习NDN的好方法。
or developers use to work
或者开发者用来工作的
with other development technologies.
与其他开发技术一起使用。
But then we can use some tooling
但接下来我们可以使用一些工具
to generate code and
生成代码和
documentation for the targeted environment,
针对目标环境的文档。
which can be NDN.
我们可能想要尝试使用NDN的情况下。
In case we want to experiment with NDN or
在我们可能想要尝试使用NDN的情况下，或者
messaging platform for IP,
消息平台用于IP，
if we want to deploy
如果我们想要部署~!@#$%^&*()
IP environment with pub/sub.
IP环境中具有发布/订阅功能。
But the key here is
但关键在于
the data-centric security and
数据中心安全和
NDN can play an important role as an enabler
NDN可以作为一个重要的促进者发挥作用
of this abstraction or
这种抽象或者
unification of these different technologies.
这些不同技术的统一。
This leads us to
这引导我们去
some open questions and some thoughts.
一些开放性的问题和一些思考。
One can be a content encryption
一个可以是内容加密
and description in pub/sub protocols,
和在发布/订阅协议中的描述，
which should be added
应当被添加
and be transparent to applications.
并且对应用程序来说应该是透明的。
This has been demonstrated
这已经得到了证明。
with data-centric in syncps.
与数据为中心的同步过程中。
Access control may be useful to
访问控制可能对...有用
have in the same way.
可能同样有用。
Also again, high-level
同样地，高层次的
description of pub/sub API
发布/订阅 API 的描述
with both communication aspects
与通信的双方面
and security in the same definition.
和安全在同一个定义中。
Here also, there is some work we
在这里，我们也有一些工作可以利用，
can leverage for us,
可以为我们利用，
trust schema and security description,
信任模式和安全描述，
which is a VerSec.
这是一个VerSec。
Also AsyncAPI is not required but it's
但是AsyncAPI不是必需的，它是
a pretty good way to
represent the pub/sub interactions.
represent the pub/sub interactions.
代表发布/订阅交互。
Also new users can be introduced to
也可以向新用户介绍
NDN from familiar concepts such
NDN从熟悉的概念开始讲起，
as first API application development
作为首个API应用程序开发
and pub/sub model.
和发布/订阅模型。
Also migration tools can be envisioned to
还可以设想出用于迁移的工具，以
migrate from IP to
可以迁移到IP协议的NDN应用程序，或者相反。
NDN applications or vice versa.
NDN应用程序或相反。
Last point, not related to
最后一点，与此无关
development is the extension of
发展是……的延伸
the Digital-Twin service I mentioned before
我之前提到的数字孪生服务
in the other research area of multiverse.
在多元宇宙的其他研究领域。
We plan to extend it to NDN for
我们计划将其扩展到NDN以实现
configuration management and error detection.
配置管理和错误检测。
This will be more critical
这将会更加重要。
when more features will
当更多功能将会
be added to NDN-DPDK,
将被添加到NDN-DPDK中，
which has distributed routing.
将会有分布式路由。
That's it for me. Thank you.
这就是我的全部了。谢谢。
>> It's like Jay got disconnected.
>> 看起来Jay好像掉线了。
But I guess we can move
但我想我们可以继续进行下去
to the next presentation
继续进行下一场演示
by Xinyu Ma on NDN forwarder manager demo.
Xinyu Ma 主持的NDN前向器管理器演示。
Xinyu works with [inaudible]
Xinyu 与 [无法听清] 合作
Phd student at UCLA. Go ahead please.
加州大学洛杉矶分校的博士研究生。请继续。
>> This is just advertisement
这只是广告。
for the NDN for the manager,
为经理的NDN，
which is GUI tools that implements
哪个是实现了 GUI 工具的
the AFT Management Protocol
AFT 管理协议
so you do not need to
所以你不需要
remember those command lines.
记住那些命令行。
First let us just start
首先，我们就开始吧。
AFT and then start the folder manager.
然后启动文件夹管理器。
You can see here will be our icon for
这里将会是我们的图标
the folder manager and we click "Save it".
文件夹管理器，我们点击“保存”。
It will open a browser UI.
它将打开一个浏览器界面。
We can see the Forwarder Status and all
我们可以看到转发器状态和所有
existing phases and our routing strategies.
现有的阶段和我们的路由策略。
Here is the Face Event notification screen,
这是面部事件通知界面，
and there is Auto Configuration button.
这里有一个自动配置按钮。
This auto configuration
这个自动配置按钮实际上将其连接到
actually connects it to
实际上将其连接到
the testbed and the AFT/NDN routs.
将其连接到测试平台和AFT/NDN路由。
If we just click this button,
如果我们只是点击这个按钮，
and we can see that they
我们可以看到他们
automatically have faced to
自动面向
the most near the testbed note.
最接近测试平台的注释。
You can also manually add the faces here.
你也可以在这里手动添加表情。
Just input the IP
只需输入IP地址
addresses and click "Create",
只需输入IP地址并点击“创建”，
it will create a new face,
它将创建一个新的界面，
and the other configuration also
它将创建一个新的界面，并且其他配置也会有路由/NDN指向新的界面ID。
have routes/NDN to the new face ID.
将有路由/NDN指向新的界面ID。
Then, this is the face we created.
接着，这就是我们创建的界面。
Again, we can manually
接着，我们可以手动
create routes if we need just here.
如果我们需要的话，就在这里创建路由。
Here we have implement NDN Ping tool.
这里我们已经实现了NDN Ping工具。
This is actually ping,
这实际上是ping，
which means we can give express
这意味着我们可以快速提供服务。
customize interest and download the result.
定制兴趣并下载结果。
For example, if we just do /NDN,
例如，如果我们只做/NDN，
this CanBePrefix and not MustBeFresh if you
如果您这样做，可以是CanBePrefix而不必是MustBeFresh。
just get some random data on the NDN testbed.
随机获取一些NDN测试床上的数据。
Here we can get response time
在这里我们可以获得响应时间。
and freshness appearance and content type.
以及新鲜度、外观和内容类型。
We are able to download this ping.
我们能够下载这个ping。
After we download this, this would be
在我们下载之后，这将会是
the contents of this data packets.
这些数据包的内容。
When we are finished with this face,
我们处理完这个面之后，
we can also delete this face by clicking
我们也可以通过点击来删除这个面。
the button here to remove this face here,
点击这里的按钮来删除这个面。
and corresponding results will
和相应的结果将会
be automatically removed also.
将会被自动移除。
Here also we have our key management team.
这里我们也有我们的关键管理团队。
It's a tree.
这是一棵树。
This is all the identities.
这是所有的身份。
The star means the default identity.
星号代表默认身份。
If I click on identity,
如果我点击身份，
we can get a list of keys and
我们可以获取一个密钥列表和
by clicking on the key we
通过点击密钥我们
can get a certificate.
我们可以获得一个证书。
We can add a key to NDMCC identity and
我们可以给NDMCC身份添加一个密钥。
also we can create a new identity, a test-2.
我们还可以创建一个新的身份，一个test-2。
It will automatically create
它将会自动创建
identity ndncc key chain.
身份ndncc密钥链。
Here is our default key.
这是我们的默认密钥。
We can also delete the key here.
我们也可以在这里删除密钥。
the existing
我们也可以删除现有的
key or certificate by clicking here.
我们也可以删除现有的密钥或证书，通过点击这里。如果你关闭了NFD，
If you shutdown NFD,
如果你关闭了NFD，
then control center says
那么控制中心就会显示
NFD is not running
NFD未在运行
and if you start it again,
如果你再次启动它，
it shows it's running again,
它显示它再次运行起来，
and every function will work.
每个功能都将正常工作。
That's it. The code is published to Github.
就是这样。代码已经发布到Github上了。
>> Thank you very much. Not sure
>> 非常感谢。不确定
whether there's anything on Slack.
是否有什么消息在Slack上。
There are some suggestions,
有一些建议，
I guess from David,
我猜是来自David的，
Xinyu take a look
新宇看一下
and continue the discussion there.
并在那里继续讨论。
Jay I can see you but we couldn't hear you.
杰伊，我能看见你，但我们听不到你。
It's the end of this session.
这是本次会议的结束。
[LAUGHTER] Thank you very much
非常感谢您
Jay and all the
Jay和所有的~!@#$%^&*()
speakers for the interesting thoughts.
感谢所有发言者的有趣想法。
Also thanks to all
也感谢所有
the participants who stayed
参与者们留下来了
this late especially our
参与者们留下来了，尤其是我们这些晚来的欧洲和亚洲的朋友，
European and Asian friends,
欧洲和亚洲的朋友们，
I can still see
我仍然可以看到
a few names on BlueJeans attendee list.
蓝牛（BlueJeans）参会名单上的几个名字。
With that, I guess
那么，我猜
I'll see you all tomorrow at 10:00
我明天10:00见你们。
AM Eastern Time and
~!@#$%^&*()
have a nice rest of your day everyone.
祝大家有一个愉快的一天。
Bye.
再见。